hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast
I help you make more money in a coaching
and online course business as well as
work on the mindset and business
strategies that are going to make you
more money and today this is going to be
all about business strategy and if
you're in my client growth accelerator
group this training came straight out of
that group with my high level coaching
clients and so don't sleep on this
training this is going to be really
supplemental to what we've been talking
about in the group it's not a whole
course that I wanted to create but I am
probably going to add this podcast as a
bonus lesson to the copywriting Mastery
course that we have because
its value to you is
phenomenal so there's two things that
I've noticed
when working with people and writing
their copy and helping coach them and
write their copy that they miss
and it's it's a natural thing to miss
it's one of the number one things I used
to miss when I wrote copy
um and it's actually the number one
thing that makes your copy convert
better so that's why I want to help you
so that you don't miss things
that are going to make you a lot of
money
two things
number one get
as specific
as possible
with your client what are their needs
what are their desires what are they
going through you might say well I have
a wide range of clients
so I can't put all of their needs out
there you don't have to honor
every single need desire or problem that
people have but just a few of them a few
of them that people can relate to
because that's the type of person that
you're going to attract when you
verbalize
and it's not really verbalizing because
you're typing it when you're writing
sales copy but when you write out
the very specific issues people are
having
here's a very specific issue that
somebody's having
if you're afraid of a runaway credit
card with Facebook ads where they charge
you a whole bunch of money and you can't
stop it because your ads aren't
converting
that's a real problem
I've heard people mention that problem
it doesn't happen by the way if you're
worried about that you've set a budget
in Facebook as long as you set your
budget and when you want the ad to end
they won't spend more than that
where runaway ads come from is when you
set too high of a budget don't log in
and check it so it's actually more of a
personal responsibility issue than an
ads manager issue
but I digress
get very specific about the problems
that people have
you're not converting clients
parenting you're dealing with a a fussy
baby at night or or you're dealing with
a teenager that talks back runs out of
the house and goes and does drugs you
know I mean
that's a dark issue but it's a reality
and it's a real issue that even the best
parents and the best
mentors I'm realizing there's like 30
people down the street over here while
I'm recording this podcast so I'm gonna
turn around
it's funny when I'm recording the
podcast while I walk around people look
at me all the time like really strange
like are you filming me no I'm not so
I'm gonna go this way
you want to get very specific about the
problems
that people are having
and you want to to verbalize them
and
you're not going to put every problem
out there
but you're going to put some of the
common issues that people have if you
see them keep coming up that affect the
result that the person is looking for so
what you look at is of the people who
are going to buy from you
what problems do they have
and you get very specific about those
not like you don't want to use words
like are you stuck do you have goals
you've got to get specific about what
those goals are
you have to get specific about what
stock
looks like
what have they done already to get
unstuck
what have they tried what hasn't worked
what goals have they had for a while how
have their goals changed
how have they progressed
you know a goal of somebody making money
get more specific what does making more
money mean to them
you know for me
if I'm looking to
buy a private jet so that I can travel
around and make video games
that's a lot more specific of a goal
than
somebody who wants to make 10 grand to
pay off their credit cards so you see
what I'm saying
is one is do you like do you want to do
you want to replace a job income
or do you want to like become the next
Elon Musk level
for me I have
no cap on my goals I'm like if if my
life takes me to that place where I have
hundreds of billions of dollars to do
with
I love it and and that's the trajectory
that I'm headed down that's the
trajectory of the life that I'm creating
for myself and and my family and I'm
excited too for those of you that know
my mom she's getting into private equity
and she's been
trading stocks and we've been learning
together
how to invest how do you
grow your income after you've made it
you know if you make a million dollars
my mom estimated
because if she had started investing
when she got into business 29 years ago
on the low end she probably would have
had at least 250 million dollars
in a portfolio by now
and so we look back like okay you can't
have regret you can't have shame you
can't have guilt for what could have
been what can we do now and that's
what's exciting is she's grown a
portfolio in the last year to multiple
Millions I've grown mine too uh almost
twenty five thousand dollars
Import in stocks in the last year it's
amazing
whereas I wasn't investing prior to that
other than buying a house or or doing
basic Investments that people do and so
our family is learning about these
specific goals and so
if I was looking for a mentor there's a
reason I'm telling you this story if I
was looking for a mentor that was going
to help me
with that I want to find a mentor
that can help me get into private equity
take the money that we have
invest it in a way that we can grow
at a faster scale in emerging
Technologies
okay
versus if somebody's like hey I'm just
going to teach you how to make more
money like
they could do that by the way I want
this I want to give you this example
let's take it back for a second
there could be
a person out there coach trainer Mentor
I actually know a guy that does this
it's a great example
um but if his copy said Jeremiah I'm
going to show you how to make more money
I would write it off as not a good fit
for me because he wasn't specific as to
how I defined that for myself
he wasn't specific as to the goal and
the result that he leads me to
okay
and so you gotta gotta gotta get more
specific
the biggest caveat that I see to why
people don't get specific is they want
to be all things to all people they want
to help a wide range of people
and that ends up hurting them in their
goals
and their income
more than helping them
you think okay well if I go out there
why do a bunch of people
I'm gonna make more money you're
actually going to make a lot less that
way
and if it's an impact thing you need to
realize that you're not called to be the
savior of the world
that you're not
born to help everybody you'll always hit
a cap on your income
as long as you try to help a wide range
of people and so this is where okay we
let's look at
who's actually become our clients for me
I want to work with
expert sales people who are also
really good at teaching and speaking
and if they're a good teacher they're a
good speaker
and they're a great salesperson I can
make them
over 10 million a year in income
and if they're not
I can actually train them how to be a
better teacher a better speaker a better
salesperson and then how to get those
clients and my system applies
for
pretty much anybody who's a coach
trainer
Mentor author to become that sort of
Famous
influencer Brand like you wrote a book
and now you might be on the Ellen show
and you're doing a
a broadcast about
the book that you just wrote and so
those are the type of clients that I can
work best with are people that are
charismatic
but if you're not charismatic if you're
not a great salesperson I can help raise
you up to that level and that's what we
do in our client growth accelerators I
got classes
to help you with that that's what this
podcast is helping you with
okay
you got to get specific about the issue
that you help people with
you got to get specific
about
the exact
experience
that people have and then the second
thing is this and it ties right into
specificity is how do you actually tell
the specifics back to the client
storytelling
you tell
a story
about their life back to them
so let's say that you help a certain
person
who is dealing with trouble trying to
conceive and get pregnant
okay so that's like a health coach type
of a thing
that specific you want to tell their
story have you tried everything the
sleepless nights maybe you've been
afraid and sad and and wished
that things didn't have to be this way
telling that story
getting into the emotions with them and
telling their story back to them shows
that you care and that you understand
and if you're lacking that story
underneath your headline
on your landing page on your sales page
you're gonna really miss a lot of
potential
in your sales copy because
you want that story to really
describe the pain
you want the people reading it to have
empathy for the pain
and to feel wow this person knows my
pain I know your pain
that type of thing you want people to be
like wow
they know exactly what I've gone through
and so
this goes directly into your sales copy
and this is The Epiphany Bridge
in the Jasper recipe that we've created
you can have it run through the Epiphany
Bridge
and the Epiphany bridge is it creates a
sort of a fictional story
that people can tell
that applies to
their life how did somebody get to the
result that you're telling
and this is part of why we bring the
hero's journey
into all aspects of our sales
copywriting of our product development
is every single person that you're
helping every single person that you're
coaching is on a journey
and they're at a different stage in
their Journey
and they have different Adventures that
they're going on
and this is why I treat
coaching from the aspect of almost like
a Choose Your Own Adventure role-playing
video game type adventure story
to where
you're the guide and the person that
you're marketing to is the player
let me explain what I mean by that okay
let's say that you fired up a video game
and you're in this new world and you
meet a guide that gives you a sword
and now with that sword you can go out
and slay the enemies right basic
storytelling Trope of video games and
even movies and TV shows
we've all seen stories of that where
uh
a lonely traveler feels called to
Adventure and finds a mentor that gives
them a weapon that they can use to then
go to the next level in their life
or in their business
and that's what you're doing is you're
giving people tools
but you're selling them on those tools
and you're selling them on inviting them
on the adventure
and many times it's by saying
traveler I know what you're going
through I know what you're dealing with
because I've been there before I've
dealt with it before
I've experienced it before
I've helped other people that have dealt
with it before
and so what happens is
that when you then run an ad
and the right person
finds your ad find your landing page
they read this story it's specific to
the adventure that they're on
they end up then taking the next step
and going into the portal with you what
is the portal
it's them giving you their name and
email address
it's them signing up with you
it's them purchasing from you
and so they go to the next level
with you and you get to get them into a
virtual event where you teach them and
you equip them and you train them and
you give them the tools that they need
to go on their adventure to the next
level
and that could be your free training
that could be your free ebook or your
audiobook or
whatever it is
that you're offering to people
okay
and so
translate that into your sales copy
think about okay
where are these people along their
Journey
what stage on their Journey are they at
how long have they been
going about this journey what struggles
have they run into along the way and if
you if you don't have the answers to
this these questions a
ask people
go out there and ask people this is why
you need to grow in your self-esteem and
stop being worried about pissing people
off disappointing them them rejecting
you
because you can't operate from a place
of being so worried about what other
people think about you and then you have
to now go out there and ask people about
their deep dark secrets and what they're
struggling with and what they're dealing
with if you're so afraid all the time of
what everybody else thinks about you if
you're so afraid
all the time about pissing people off
about upsetting people about angering
people I got people
all the time
on my social media
who are angry with me for running ads
they're angry with me I had a guy get
livid at me because my presentation I
took 30 minutes to dive into the main
training content
he got pissed off at this fact that I
didn't do what he wanted and he wanted
to make sure that I knew that I've
gotten nasty letters from people
because I didn't do what they wanted
that's fine I don't care it doesn't it
doesn't bother me anymore
because that's part of that process
and so you're gonna have to learn to go
out there
to talk to to stop filtering yourself to
stop trying to
to play it safe and not upset people and
not walk on toes and not Rock the Boat
and start asking questions for the
things that you don't know yet about
your client become Uber curious
becomes super curious
as much as possible
in your everyday day to day what are my
target prospects going through
what are they dealing with
what are they struggling with
what is knocking them off track what
goals do they have what deep dark
secrets have they not told me yet
what deep dark or bright desires do they
have that they haven't told anybody
what secret desires do they have and
that when you show
the prospect that you understand what
they want you understand what they've
gone through you know the pain they've
experienced and you tell their story
back to them and you get very very
specific
in your sales copy
this attracts the right people to you at
the best cost and creates better
conversions
for your sales letters
and for your marketing okay
and so and there's another layer that
you can take to this is you can use chat
GPT or Jasper
and ask these tools you can type in
question you know
tell me what are some of the struggles
that somebody who would go through this
webinar experiencing describe to me the
top 20 goals that they might have
describe to me the top 20 problems that
might stop them from taking action
describe to me the top 20 issues as to
why people don't
do XYZ
and so then you can filter that back
through
your sales letter
the AI
um but here's one thing that you can
actually have the AI do is let's say
that you wrote a sales letter
this is kind of more of an advanced
level thing for my client growth
accelerator people so if you're
listening to this this is going to be
something that
is just going to rock your socks
take your existing sales letter
and tell chat GPT or Jasper
take this reference material and act as
if
you're the target person who would sign
up for this webinar and become a client
of our training and coaching program
so the AI ends up looking at your
webinar and pretending like they are
that person and then start to ask it
questions as if you're asking somebody
else
what's the biggest thing that stopped
you
from moving forward to reach your goals
what's the biggest the top five
struggles over the last five years that
have prevented you
from taking your business to the next
level
what are the top 10
reasons why
you you think that you're still stuck
what are the top
10 frustrations
that you have about
creating your business and reaching your
goals that have prevented you
for making the kind of money that you
want to make
and so what you can do is when you do
this you can actually ask Jasper and
chat CPT to be in the place of
a Target client
to be in the place of a potential
customer and then to answer those
questions for you and so then you can
take those answers and filter them right
back into your sales letter and you can
ask a question of chat CPT you know
write a sales letter taking these issues
into account and maybe take one of those
issues and you can make a webinar about
that by exploring what are the things
that these people go through
if you don't have actual people that you
can get feedback from you can use
artificial intelligence to be a stand-in
for your market research
the AI can be a stand-in
for the type of client that you want to
work with by telling it to act as if
they're the right person for your
webinar and then you start asking
basically you're training the algorithm
to respond as if they're that person and
it will give you pretty accurate
responses
from that they're obviously when you're
using AI none of the responses are
guaranteed none of them are perfect none
of them are going to produce the type of
result that you want
right out the gate you're gonna have to
edit them you're gonna have to discern
yourself is this really a good fit is
this really the type of person that I'm
trying to connect with and communicate
with and that's going to be up to you to
decide really
but this is going to help you along the
way to do more of that market research
and then Implement some of those
specific issues you can ask chat gbt
write us a creative storyline about
somebody
who is having XYZ problem and
received XYZ solution or experienced XYZ
solution you type that in off of your
market research and it will start to
help help you reverse engineer
this into stories here's another thing
and last thing I'm going to leave you
with another AI command that you can do
as you can have it say okay write a
creative story about somebody who had
XYZ problem and is experiencing XYZ a
result or solution then you can say
rewrite this story
as bullet point
headlines framed as a question
to use on a sales letter
and I've done this
and it will actually rewrite
the storyline as headlines that people
can use for their sales letter so it'll
actually take the story like John was
experiencing this and he found a program
and it did this and it'll rewrite it as
are you experiencing
XYZ problem and that problem will be
related to the same story that it wrote
about John potentially if you've never
used the AI to do this I highly
recommend that you download and use chat
GPT and Jasper and start using these
tools to start to create better sales
copy and better marketing
for your business
and you can have it take a creative
story reframe it as headlines that then
you can use
for your sales letter by using different
commands like take this creative story
and rewrite it as a bullet point
headline question
to invite people to join a webinar
something like that and that's how you
can then iterate through and turn these
questions and these stories and these
ideas into sales copy that you can use
so hopefully these tips have helped you
again this is going to be a bonus lesson
as part of my high level paid coaching
Community as well and I think this is
really going to help you these two
things getting specific and dialing in
your storytelling that's going to help
you get more sales in your coaching and
online course business we'll talk soon
everybody have a good one